[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[ENGINE REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TRUCK HORN BLARES]
[LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GUNSHOT]
[FIREWORKS EXPLODING]
- [ENGINES REVVING]
- [BUS HORN HONKS]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- [GUNSHOT]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [TRUCK HORN HONKS]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
I was telling them
how I got even more blessings
ever since I purchased
Ginintuang Lupa.
Those informal settlers
will have to leave that place!
They robbed Salvador.
Clearly, that idiot got bolder!
And there's the man
who saved me.
He was so brave, boss!
This is so good.
We can use this!
Find the man who
went up against Paquito's men.
Well, Gabo here wanted to treat
us to some food and drinks.
But since we were
with these three,
we got in trouble.
Why'd you have to work
for Gabo's enemy?
I'm so sick of being poor!
If that's what you want,
then suit yourself!
What could
they be fighting about?
Uncle Rudy also sounds mad.
Sounds pretty intense.
Maybe it's about Betchay
working at Paquito's bar.
Why would Betchay work there?
What a shame.
Ma, don't say that.
Aunt Betchay might hear you.
She might come for us.
Oh, why? It's true.
Hold up.
Watch your words, Aunt Diday.
My Grandma works there too.
It's the truth.
You know what's odd?
Aunt Betchay got hired
at Paquito's bar.
Django is Gabo's enemy.
That smells like trouble.
This I know for sure.
Uncle Paquito and Django
will get back at Gabo
through Aunt Betchay.
I knew them too well.
I know how their minds work.
I'm sure of it.
Let's just ignore them.
We might get dragged too.
[TOLITS] Oh, she's coming.
[LAUGHTER, OVERLAPPING CHATTER]
That's funny!
Of course, we're just
talking about food...
- What are you guys looking at?
- Oh, Aunt Bechay...
You're talking about me,
aren't you?
If you've nothing better to do,
don't dip your toes
in other people's business!
That woman is something.
I told you she'd get mad at us.
Why?
What I said is true!
Even if we don't have money,
I wouldn't take
that kind of work.
Imagine showing my body
to random men?
I'd rather rummage
through trash!
Diday, even if you expose
your body in front of men,
no one will look at you!
- [SLAPS]
- [ALL] Ooh!
If I find out you're going
to that bar,
I'll beat you up real good!
- [BLOW LANDS]
- Oh!
Don't embarrass me
in front of them.
- Relax, Diday.
- Diday, sit down, come on.
Keep the shots coming!
- [CHUCKLES]
- [BOTTLES CLINKING]
Don't make her mad.
[FAINT CHATTER IN DISTANCE]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
[GABO INHALES DEEPLY]
Pa...
I'm not sure if I'm the one
who should be telling you this.
[GABO INHALES DEEPLY]
But I just wish...
you didn't allow
Auntie Betchay to work
in Uncle Paquito's beerhouse.
It's dangerous for her
to be there.
Django might get back at her.
We tried to stop her.
But that's what she wants.
She wouldn't take
the job there...
if I hadn't gotten shot.
It hurts seeing you hurt.
This isn't right.
I can imagine what the men
around here think of you.
In the whole community.
But don't worry, Pa.
Once I get a job...
we won't let her work
in a place like that anymore.
[RUDY BREATHES DEEPLY]
Thank you, son.
But...
I am the man of the house.
I should be the one working...
to provide our family's needs.
It's embarrassing
to admit but...
your Auntie Betchay is the one
making money to provide for us.
Ever since Betchay
and I got together,
she has always been the one
doing everything
for this family.
[MUSIC TURNS SOFT]
And...
she never left us behind.
I'm very grateful for her.
When we lost your mother,
I lost my way too.
I forgot...
I forgot I can find love again.
And your Auntie Betchay,
she was just my friend.
I didn't promise
anything to her.
I couldn't give anything to her.
But...
whatever happens,
she didn't leave us.
You and I.
[FIRE CRACKLING]
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC PLAYING]
Daddy.
Where are we?
This is where I grew up.
And this will be your new home.
Son, from now on,
you'll call me Papa.
We've got to belong here.
Yes, Papa.
Let's go.
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
[YOUNG RUDY] We'll move in here,
son, with your Aunt Mameng.
Rudy?
[SQUEALS] Oh, Rudy!
Rudy, it really is you!
What a surprise!
Oh my!
You've been gone forever!
Are you moving back here?
Where have you been, anyway?
[SNIFFS]
You smell so good!
Hey there, you little cutie!
What's your name?
I'm Gabriel.
Gabriel.
[GIGGLES] You look so handsome,
just like your father.
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
Where's your mother?
She's dead.
Rudy?
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
Rudy!
- Big sis.
- [YOUNG MAMENG] Oh my...
This is Gabriel, my son.
Gabriel.
Such a handsome boy.
Come on, let's head inside.
- Follow me.
- That's your Aunt Mameng.
[YOUNG MAMENG EXHALES]
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [GLASS THUDS]
- Dinner's ready.
I brought something
to go with your drink.
Chicken intestines.
Three skewers of them.
[GIGGLES]
Here.
The little one's asleep now.
Where's Mameng?
She's away.
She went to Cebu.
[YOUNG BETCHAY] Hmm.
What's that?
I thought this would be
the turning point in my life.
- What exactly happened to you?
- [ZIPPER RASPS]
You didn't come home
for eight years.
- [BOTTLE SCRAPES]
- [ALCOHOL SLOSHING]
I don't want
to discuss it, Betchay.
I'd rather not
remember the past.
[GLOOMY MUSIC PLAYING]
Rudy, how can I be there for you
if you won't share
what you've gone through?
Let's just say that I thought
I had finally struck luck.
That my life had changed.
But no.
No, I was still cursed.
I lost everything.
[GLOOMY MUSIC CONTINUES]
You have to work hard
for things in life.
Not everything can be left
to luck.
But if you feel like
you've lost it all...
Rudy, you can still start again.
How can I start over, Betchay?
All I know is being a mechanic.
[CHAIR SCRAPING]
Rudy...
How about we work together?
I have money.
I can give you capital.
Let's make
all your dreams happen.
Didn't you want a repair shop?
I'll give you one.
I know someone who owns
a house with a big yard.
We can set it up there.
I'll help you.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[GLASS THUDS]
[DOOR OPENS]
Hi!
- Hi, Betchay!
- Where's your father?
He's not around.
Oh, really?
[YOUNG BETCHAY] Ah.
What's that?
A dish for your
good-looking father!
[SOFT MUSIC PLAYING]
It smells delicious!
You're hungry, huh?
[GIGGLES]
[CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
Alright, dig in.
[YOUNG BETCHAY GIGGLES]
What's this?
Leftover food.
So tasty,
just like fried chicken!
It's our specialty here
in Tondo.
[SOFT MUSIC CONTINUES]
- Hey...
- Mmm!
Do you have any rice?
Wait, let me check.
Hey, Gabriel, leave some
for your father, alright?
Rudy?
Come on now, Rudy.
Get up.
Sit properly.
Rudy, please...
- [YOUNG BETCHAY SIGHING]
- [GRUNTS]
- What's the matter with you?
- [SIGHS]
Come on.
Rudy, what's happening with you?
[GULPING]
Do you want your son
to see you like this?
You're always drunk.
There's a child living here too.
[YOUNG RUDY SIGHS]
Rudy, my love,
I'm sorry, but...
...no amount of drinking
will bring your wife back.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
That's enough.
Stop. Give me that.
It's over.
Let's get you to bed.
- I want...
- No, you can't.
Rudy-- Oh my!
Rudy!
Oh my!
Rudy, wait--
- [HEAVY THUD]
- [RUDY BREATHES DEEPLY]
[VOICE SHAKING] Rudy...
Whatever happened in the past,
forget it.
It's already behind you.
Set yourself free.
There are so many people
who love you.
No matter how much we want it,
it won't change the fact that
your wife is gone.
No one can ever replace
Belinda in my heart.
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[SNIFFLES]
[YOUNG RUDY] No one...
[YOUNG BETCHAY
BREATHES SHAKINGLY]
[YOUNG RUNDY WHIMPERS]
No one...
- [CRYING QUIETLY]
- No one...
I'll help you.
[BREATHES DEEPLY, SNIFFLES]
I've loved you for a long time.
- [MUMBLING]
- [SNIFFLES]
Let me help you.
I'll do anything
to make you love me.
[SNIFFLING]
- [GRUNTS]
- [SNIFFLES]
[YOUNG RUDY SIGHS]
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC CONTINUES]
[YOUNG RUDY GROANS SOFTLY]
[SNIFFLES]
I love you.
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC CONTINUES]
[SNIFFLES]
I know all of that, Pa.
I know it was Aunt Betchay
who hustled
to provide for us.
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC CONTINUES]
And I witnessed...
how hurt you were
when Mama died.
But, Pa...
Don't be discouraged.
Don't lose hope.
I'm here to help you.
I know, Gabo.
Nothing can compare
to my love for your mother.
I've made many wrong decisions
and countless mistakes.
But I only did
all those things...
...to give you a good life.
I just hope, son...
one day...
I hope you find...
a woman who will truly love you
and change your life.
[SOFT MUSIC PLAYING]
[SNIFFLES]
[SIGHS]
Why are you suddenly so quiet?
Have you found someone?
Someone who will love you?
[SIGHS DEEPLY]
Not yet, Pa.
And that's not on my mind
right now.
All I want right now...
...is to improve our lives
and help you.
But if ever I find
a woman to love,
I want to be like you.
Because I saw how much
affection you had for Mama,
how you took care of her,
and how you made us
feel loved.
I really look up to you
as a father.
As a parent.
I love you so much, Pa.
I love you so much.
[SNIFFLES]
[SOFT MUSIC CONTINUES]
Hey, make sure that's clean.
And arrange the chairs.
It looks like a mess right now.
And you four!
Once a customer comes in,
offer food and drinks
right away.
Make sure they will order.
Hey, Betchay!
Why are you late?
- Uh...
- Wow, Betchay.
You just got here,
but you're looking like
you're ready for closing time.
Sorry. Rudy and I had a spat.
That's why I'm late.
Well, don't bring
your personal problems here.
Yeah! That's bad for business!
- True.
- Betchay.
Our customers here
are mostly jeepney drivers
and construction workers.
They work themselves to
the bone every day.
Yes, that's why we must
entertain them
and help them
relieve their stress.
Well, sorry.
I'm sorry, okay?
Keep in mind, Betchay,
that you're just new here.
So, you must prove yourself.
And you have a deal
with Boss Paquito, right?
If you bring in money, he'd let
you keep working here.
- Remember?
- Yes, yes.
So, can you forget about
your problem with Rudy
even just for tonight?
Can you do that?
- Well, you have to.
- Yeah.
Smile and show off
your cleavage
so you can attract customers.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
How's your father doing?
He's fine now.
I can't believe Betchay.
What was she thinking?
[MAMENG]
She's so stubborn.
What should we do to stop her
from working at that bar?
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
I don't know, Auntie.
[UPBEAT BAR MUSIC
BLARING ON SPEAKERS]
- Hi! Hello!
- Good evening!
Want to sit by the electric fan?
The lighting over there
makes me extra pretty.
Just one bottle? Make it two!
- Alright. I'll have two.
- Two beers, please!
I'll have a bottle, too.
See that wench?
She's stealing our customers!
It seems she's no longer upset.
Good thing she listened to us.
- Ugh!
- She must really need money.
[CUSTOMER]
I really love drinking with you!
Me, too!
You're so cute! [GIGGLING]
- Give us another bucket!
- Order some bar chow too.
We have a special promo.
[CUSTOMER]
I'll have some bar chow too!
- Bar chow for this table!
- [GIGGLING]
- Drink up!
- Betchay...
Take it easy on the alcohol.
It's too early to get drunk.
You're only on
your first customer.
- I can handle it. [GIGGLES]
- Really? [FORCED LAUGHTER]
- Cheers!
- Oh! Okay!
- Sir, enjoy!
- Cheers!
- Enjoy.
- Let's drink our hearts out!
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Boss, am I really going
to follow what's in the script?
Just tell them that a group
of men went after you
-because you exposed the police!
- And then what?
I beat them all up?
Yeah! Follow it up by saying
that you studied wushu,
taekwondo, or wrestling!
Say that you're a black belter
with a black eye too!
[ARNEL CLEARS THROAT]
Here. Use this.
Looks cool.
[QUIRKY MUSIC PLAYING]
[ARNEL] There you go!
Perfect!
Challenge all those villains
and ask them, "How much
is your dignity?"
[LAUGHING] Boss.
Salvador...
[IN UNISON] The Avenger is here!
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [CLACKS]
[SALVADOR] Salvador
"The Avenger" Manalo.
Protector of the oppressed.
[ACTION MUSIC PLAYING]
- [BLOW LANDS]
- [THUDS]
- [GUNSHOTS]
- [GUN COCKS]
[ACTION MUSIC CONTINUES, FADES]
[CHAIR CLATTERS]
Until when do you plan on
being trampled over?
You are being abused
every single day!
If you can't defend yourselves,
if you're scared,
call out to me!
Salvador, The Avenger!
The protector of the oppressed.
Hurry up!
That should've been washed
ages ago!
- Quick, get out there!
- Sweetie!
- What?
- Check this out!
- What is it?
- Just look at it!
- Huh?
- Look at it!
[SALVADOR] The demolition
issue at Ginintuang Lupa
is making a lot of noise.
I followed it closely!
A group of men ambushed me.
I just know that General Jacinto
and the police
sent them to attack me.
That Salvador is blabbering
his mouth again!
You know what to do.
I'll leave it to you.
Huh? What do you mean
you'll leave it to me?
- What exactly are you leaving?
- Huh?
Didn't Ma'am Isobel mention it?
If we acquired new information,
we should report it immediately.
Then let's go together!
So that if they turn violent
because of so much anger,
- they'll strangle you first.
- Huh?
- Go, lead the way! Go!
- Huh? You go first!
[TOTO WHISPERING] Hurry!
Wh-- where did they go?
Oh, over there!
Quick, wave at her!
- Get her attention!
- [WHISPERING] Ma'am!
[TWINKLE] Psst! Ma'am!
[TWINKLE] Ma'am!
[QUIRKY STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
Excuse me for a bit.
I'll be back.
[TWINKLE PANTING]
What is it? It's like you're
drowning from all that waving!
Didn't you and sir tell us
to give you an update
when you're being called out?
Well, here it is!
- Huh? Right now?
- Yes!
But I think it's better
if you check it yourselves.
[ISOBEL] What? Right now?
- Yes, ma'am?
- I don't want to!
What's the commotion about?
- What's that?
- [TWINKLE] Watch it--
Ma'am, uh...
Is it something I need to see?
Give it here!
Sir--
[TOTO SIGHS]
- Sir...
- [RICARDO SIGHS]
[SALVADOR] This morning,
a group of men ambushed me.
I have a feeling they want
to get rid of me
because I called out
Ricardo Jacinto and the police
regarding the demolishment
at Ginintuang Lupa.
[STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
What happened?
Their threats
didn't work on me!
Here, watch this.
[BLOWS LANDING]
[SALVADOR] What now, huh?
See that?
There were so many of them
but they're no match for me!
Why is that?
I studied five kinds of martial
arts. Five!
So listen up, you dogs.
Even the person
who ordered you to do this.
You'll regret letting me live.
I'll be the one to put an end
to your depravity!
You bastards!
[GRIM MUSIC PLAYING]
Your timing is perfect,
isn't it?
But Ma'am, if we don't tell you
right away, you get mad.
You blame us!
- Blame Salvador instead!
- Get out!
- Yes, ma'am!
- [TWINKLE SCREAMING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[CATALAN] Ricardo,
looks like that reporter got you
in a spot.
The project seems to be less
and less possible.
Well, it's 'cause
the project is rich.
That's why they keep
going after it.
But I assure you,
we don't have a problem.
It's not very enticing
to invest in you right now.
As more time passes by,
people will believe that
reporter more than your vision.
You're successful
in your career,
but not in business.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Wait a minute.
Isn't this a reunion?
We shouldn't keep
talking about business.
Why don't we relax
and talk about our families?
- Ah, yes!
- Yes.
- Good idea.
- Yes. Okay.
- Have a seat!
- This is a good distraction.
- [LAUGHTER]
- Yes!
- Let's have some cheese.
- Vic.
Yes?
How are you children doing?
My daughter has been
a surgeon for 10 years.
My son, on the other hand,
is a regional court judge.
It's nice that they are
still here in the country.
After studying abroad, my
three kids won't come back home.
They say they don't see
a future in the Philippines.
That might not be the case.
Look at the father,
a highly decorated
and respected general.
- Yes.
- Very influential.
They would have
never had it so easy.
[MAN] That's the problem.
I always had to fly around
the world just to see them.
- I move around a lot.
- Wow!
In London, in Dubai,
and even in New Jersey.
- Wow!
Poor you.
That seems like such
a huge problem.
Our children know
how easy life becomes
once you become
a police officer.
My son is following
in my footsteps.
- He's already a Colonel.
- Good for you.
What about your son, Ricardo?
He would surely hold
a high rank by now.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
I wish.
I focused my attention
on him back then.
I really felt he had
what it takes.
I thought he might
be the next...
Jacinto, chief of police.
But he was taken too early.
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Ah.
But we have a daughter
who is a police officer!
Oh, look, she's right here!
- What's happening?
- [ISOBEL] Your dad's reunion.
A reunion
with his general friends!
- Auntie Vicky, hi!
- Hello.
- Hello! Hi, everybody!
- Hi!
Hi everyone.
Good evening.
Well, gentlemen,
this is my eldest daughter,
Max
- [ISOBEL] Yes.
- One hell of a cop.
- Can I tell them about it?
- [MAX] Oh!
Earlier this year,
over one weekend,
she caught three people
on the most wanted list.
- Good job!
- Wow!
The only question
I have is...
is she good or is she good?
Lieutenant,
I see you're following
your father's footsteps.
[CHUCKLES]
I'll try doing that, sir.
I'm sure
you will make him proud.
What do you mean
he will?
- [MAN] Yeah.- She will?
I'm already proud of her.
- Aww.
- [MAX] Thank you.
- Cheers!
- Cheers.
[TEKLA] We should've
went here earlier.
[WOMAN] You should've
went here instead!
[TEKLA] I know! They fought
with someone instead.
[IPE] You should've
told us earlier.
- [BINOY] He peeked at them.
- [TEKLA] Who started it?
See? I knew it.
Gabo!
Have a seat?
- Let him sit.
- What happened?
Why did Rudy
and Betchay fight?
It's because Aunt Bechay
is working at Paquito's bar.
[DIDAY] I knew it!
What Betchay did was wrong.
What did Rudy say?
- Was he angry?
- [BONG] Of course he is!
What sane man
would be happy
that his wife's body is being
desired by other men?
[TOLITS] Gabo.
I'm scared Betchay
might be in danger.
Django might
use her for revenge.
[DABOY] You need
to talk to her, Gabo.
I don't know how
I'll talk to Aunt Betchay.
But I can think of only one way.
I needed to find a decent job
So that I could support
my family.
If I do that...
Betchay doesn't have
to work at that bar anymore.
If she stays there,
her life could be in danger.
I need everyone here.
But I'll kill Mr. Chan.
This is your chance to get rid
of Samantha Jacinto, Lucas.
Do you think what
you've done will be forgotten?
Do you think they'll
remove your suspension?
That you'll remove the stain
you've done in my name?
You didn't just bring shame
in this family,
you also brought us
so much pain.
We are all devastated
over losing our brother!
I pray everyday hoping
that you'll forgive me.
Sometimes I wish
it was you who died.
My husband, Babot, was taken!
They took my father, Gabo!
I promise you we'll find him.
So this is what you're doing
to these men!
You're using them
for business!
There's nothing
you can do because
we'll slaughter you alive!